Prince Ning, Xiao Changmin,
has long coveted the throne.
He instructed a foreign lady in his
manor to keep a rare foreign poison.
I discovered Prince Ning's
treasonous intentions,
and urged him to turn back.
But he tried to murder me to silence me.
I barely managed to escape,
but the child in my womb lost its life.
Prince Ning,
fearing his crimes would be exposed,
drank poison and killed himself
in his manor.
I beg Your Majesty for justice,
and allow me and Prince Ning
to sever all ties.
=Blossoms of Power=
(Adapted from the novel, After My
Bloom, All Flowers Wither by Jin Huang)
=Episode 27=
Changmin
committed suicide out of fear
of punishment?
The Imperial Guard found some things
in Prince Ning's Manor.
But it is not my place to say more.
The Empress Dowager
and His Majesty invite you
to Yong'an Hall for a talk,
Your Highness.
Greetings, Father, Grandmother.
You may rise.
Father,
why did Changmin
take poison and kill himself?
Do not call him Changmin.
For so many years,
all of us
have been kept in the dark.
The rare poison in the palace back then
came from the hands
of the foreign lady in his manor.
This woman
is skilled in using rare poisons,
and has been hiding
in Prince Ning's Manor
for over ten years.
She has confessed
that she was instructed by Changmin.
(Confession of the Guilty Slave, Yi Sha)
(Prince Ning ordered me to make a rare poison,
a trace amount can make one wish for death.)
(Signature: Yi Sha)
The cherry cheese from back then
was poisoned by Changmin?
He coveted the position of Crown Prince
and harbored resentment.
Knowing you liked to eat cherry cheese,
he made this vicious move.
Afterwards,
he even showed concern for you.
Thinking about it now,
it truly makes one shudder.
To think the murderer
was my second prince,
he was actually so ruthless!
It truly chills my heart.
Did that foreign lady
confess it herself?
(Clarity and Serenity)
Your Highness.
Do you feel
that Prince Ning
is not the real culprit?
Changmin's so-called suicide
doesn't seem like the act
of the real culprit.
He seems more like
a pawn being manipulated.
The real mastermind behind the scenes
is still within these four palace walls.
(Prince Xin's Manor)
Brother-in-law, you're back.
I asked the kitchen
to stew some ginseng soup.
It will be brought over shortly.
What are you doing here?
I have absolutely nothing to do
with Prince Ning anymore.
I feel like
a wandering ghost.
Actually,
I've always considered your place
as my own home.
You were once my second sister-in-law.
For you to come here
is against propriety.
I have absolutely
no improper thoughts now.
I just want to be your sister,
and beg for a little pity
and protection from you.
You no longer have
any connection with this place.
Go back.
The doctor said
I lost too much blood
from the miscarriage,
and my body hasn't fully recovered yet.
I still have matters to attend to.
I'll have someone escort you back later.
Brother-in-law.
Thank you for granting
my brother's marriage, Your Majesty.
You may rise.
Xihe,
I know very well
that your father
had always been considering
the future of you and your brother.
I just wanted
to fulfill this wish for your father.
The Xue family has been
a literary family for generations,
and they are also very happy
with this marriage.
I am
able to fulfill this beautiful union,
which brings me great comfort.
I requested an audience today
to implore you
to allow me to return to northwest
to attend my brother's wedding,
Your Majesty.
Granted.
It is only natural for siblings
to share a deep bond.
However, it is a long
and arduous journey.
Xihe,
I will send an elite squad
to escort you.
Return to the East Palace
and plan carefully.
Choose an auspicious day to depart.
Thank you for your grace, Your Majesty.
(Cultivate Virtue
and Practice Righteousness)
(Imperial Capital)
From the imperial capital to northwest,
first to Shanzhou, then to Lanzhou,
and finally to Yaozhou.
The route follows the official road
with post stations at every stop.
The official road is the safest.
Are you also going to northwest?
Father said I am frail
and cannot endure a long journey.
Father is right.
Just stay in the capital
and wait for my return.
Father has sent guards to escort me,
and I have Mo Yu and Mo Yuan with me.
You don't need to worry too much.
Your Highness,
His Majesty has approved
Crown Princess's return to northwest
to attend her brother's wedding.
She will depart tomorrow.
(Taoran Inn)
Madam,
this is your premium room.
If you need anything,
just call for me anytime.
Your Highness.
Greetings, Crown Princess.
Why are you here?
I am on official duty
to inspect Shanzhou.
Perhaps...
Perhaps it is the will of Heaven
that we happen
to be traveling the same way.
It truly is destiny.
Whether by the will of Heaven
or by reason,
there is no destiny between us.
Since you are here on official duty,
let's pretend we never met.
We will go our separate ways
and not interfere with each other.
Farewell.
Zhen Zhu,
help me comb my hair.
My princess, are you satisfied?
Your Highness!
What are you doing here?
I haven't seen my wife for days.
I couldn't help myself,
so I sneaked out of the palace.
If you are angry,
you may punish me.
Leave.
You wouldn't let me come with you,
yet you had Changqing
protect you all the way.
Prince Xin is on official duty.
We just happen to be going the same way.
Why are you so petty?
Official duty?
Do you really believe that?
Is he really on official duty?
Who is it?
It's been a tiring journey.
I've prepared some pastries for you.
Please have a taste, Crown Princess.
Thank you for your kindness.
But I have already gone to bed.
This is
perilla and smoked plum cake.
It was my late consort's
favorite pastry.
She has been gone for four years.
I've kept Nanny Li in the manor
all this time.
Every year on her birthday,
I have Nanny Li
make this pastry for her.
That was your late consort's preference,
not mine.
I've disliked the taste of perilla
since I was a child.
You, get out.
I was just afraid
that being away for so long,
you would miss this taste.
Get out.
Hurry.
I'm not leaving.
Get out.
Are you alright?
I'm fine.
I just...
The Crown Princess has already changed
and gone to bed.
Please head back for now, Your Highness.
Then please give these pastries
to the Crown Princess for me.
Thank you, Your Highness.
Prince Xin!
How could you barge
into my room without permission?
I just heard a strange noise.
It's late.
I need to rest.
To avoid any suspicion
and protect both our reputations,
please leave immediately.
You didn't tell him I was here.
Were you worried about me,
or him?
I was worried about myself.
♪Amidst the flickering lights♪
♪Alone for several autumns♪
♪How to choose the one♪
♪To be with forever?♪
♪When I gaze upon you♪
♪Flower petals twirl gently in my heart♪
♪Gracefully♪
♪For all eternity♪
♪The timeless wind and moon♪
♪Quietly reflect in your sparkling eyes♪
♪Scattered red petals fall like rain♪
♪It's a wonderful time in the world♪
♪Bits of worries and sorrows♪
♪Are gently gathered
into your elegant sleeves♪
♪Gradually, on the misty path♪
♪Not a trace of sorrow can be found♪
Your Highness,
you always like to show up uninvited.
Some people are always so stubborn,
so distracted.
But I'm different from you.
You went through all the trouble
to escort your sister-in-law
from far away.
As her husband,
I am deeply grateful.
What?
Are you upset?
Why would I be?
Watching my rival get harshly rejected
by my beloved wife,
I couldn't be happier.
I have plenty of time
to stay by her side,
protect her,
and wait for her to change her mind.
But you, Crown Prince,
your days are numbered.
It's getting late.
Xihe is still waiting
for me to go to bed.
Take care, Changqing.
It's been a bumpy ride.
You should get some rest.
You look exhausted.
If you refuse to sleep,
I'll have the carriage turn back
to the posthouse,
and wait for you to catch up on sleep
before we leave.
Your Highness,
Prince Xin has been following us
on horseback.
Should we stop him?
No need.
(A Feast Under the Sky)
Come on,
let's drink to our hearts' content!
- Yeah!
Men,
come on.
Eat and drink well tonight!
- Cheers!
- Come on!
Drink up! Cheers!
Come on.
- Yeah!
Let's toast!
Cheers!
Bottoms up!
- Cheers!
- Let's toast!
Let me propose a toast as well.
(Geng Liangcheng,
Deputy General of Northwest Army)
In just three days,
it will be Young Master Shen's wedding.
This is a joyous occasion
for the entire northwest!
Today, my brothers and I
want to properly celebrate
for the Young Master!
We won't leave until we're drunk!
- Congratulations, Duke!
- Congratulations, Young Master!
Thank you for your warm hospitality,
Uncle Geng.
And thank you, Generals.
Bottoms up!
- Cheers!
- Bottoms up!
Another round.
You must have a few more drinks,
Young Master.
Come.
Have a drink with the Young Master.
Come, Young Master.
Come.
- Cheers.
- Congratulations!
Congratulations!
Come.
- We are all brothers.
- Come, cheers.
- Come on.
- Come.
Duke,
let me fill your cup.
Duke.
Fill it up.
Come, bottom's up.
- We won't leave until we're drunk.
- Let's drink.
- Cheers.
- Great.
Cheers.
- Fill them up.
- Everyone, drink up.
- We won't leave until we're drunk.
- Come on.
Fill it up.
Cheers.
All right.
Assassins!
Hurry!
Hurry! Go!
- Hurry!
- There are guards at the city gate.
Engage the enemy at once!
Keep up!
- Guards!
Where is everyone?
(Tingxi City)
Where are the city guards?
Where did they go?
- Kill them!
Father!
Duke!
Uncle Geng?
Geng Liangcheng!
You shameless traitor,
colluding with the Le tribe!
Despicable scoundrel!
How dare you plot against the Duke?
We won't let you off even as ghosts!
Shen Yueshan.
Do you remember my son, Zhongji?
You personally ordered
his beheading back then.
Today, I will kill all of you
to be buried with my son!
Yun'an,
leave me.
Take everyone and go!
Father,
I won't leave you behind.
Soldiers!
- Here!
Defend the Duke to the death!
- Defend the Duke to the death!
Fire!
Father!
How are my father and brother doing now?
At the critical moment,
fortunately, General Yan,
who was stationed outside the city,
arrived in time.
He broke through the city gates
and saved the Duke and the Young Master.
The Young Master was shot by an arrow,
but his life is not in danger.
The Duke suffered internal injuries
and lost a lot of blood.
He is still unconscious.
Mo Yuan,
take my token.
Immediately send men
to the prefectures around Tingxi City
to gather all renowned physicians
to treat the Duke.
Understood.
Set off immediately.
We must arrive by tomorrow.
Understood.
(Duke of Wei's Manor)
How is my father's condition now?
The Duke's injuries are too severe.
Although his life is saved for now,
he remains in a coma.
My father's health
will be in your hands.
I will do my utmost.
I want to go see my brother.
You should go rest for a while.
I'm not tired.
Yun'an,
Father needs you.
Northwest needs you, too.
You must recover well.
Don't worry, Xihe.
The Le tribe soldiers
who infiltrated the city
have all been wiped out by General Yan.
The city defenses have been redeployed.
The various units of Northwest Army
have been assembled,
standing by in full readiness.
So the traitor
is really Geng Liangcheng?
I saw it with my own eyes.
I remember
he used to brave life and death
with Father,
sharing his trials and tribulations.
He was also your first teacher
in martial arts
and military strategy.
Uncle Geng and his wife
have always cared for us deeply.
I really can't understand
how he could become a traitor.
It's because of
Geng Zhongji.
Uncle Geng's only son?
Geng Zhongji went missing
when he was young,
and was only found two years ago.
But he had already become a man
of corrupt morals,
running roughshod over the town
and treating human life like dirt.
Geng Liangcheng and his wife
felt guilty toward him,
often using money to bail him out,
which only fueled his evil deeds.
Father enforced the law impartially
and had Geng Zhongji beheaded in public.
Geng Liangcheng and his wife
were devastated.
But after a period of silence,
they treated Father and me
the same as before.
Thinking about it now,
how could the two of them
truly hold no grudges?
I think this matter
is not as simple as just
seeking personal revenge.
You mean...
If it were just for personal revenge,
Father had his guard completely down
around him.
If he assassinated him secretly,
his chances of success
would be much higher.
But instead,
he colluded with the Le tribe
to slaughter northwest's soldiers,
and even attempted to wipe out
the leaders of all units at once.
This is a blatant seizure of power.
You've stayed up too late.
Get some sleep.
Yun'an has his hands full right now,
and he's heavily injured.
I want to help him take care
of the matters in the rear camp.
If you collapse from exhaustion,
how would Father and Yun'an
feel about it?
I'm being too impatient.
You're right.
I should get some rest.
I'll go get you some soothing incense.
Along the way,
you haven't let your guard down
for a moment.
Just listen to me now.
Close your eyes and get some good rest.
I'll stay with you.
Who's there?
General Geng,
I hope you've been well.
Your Highness.
In this battle,
you fought beautifully.
Although Shen Yueshan didn't die,
both father and son
are now severely injured.
And the Le army
will continue to arrive
in endless streams.
The Shen family
will fall sooner or later.
Do you know the Crown Prince and Crown
Princess have arrived in Tingxi City?
You haven't even figured out
your own situation,
yet you're already scheming
on my behalf.
They came at the perfect time.
What I've been waiting for
is this exact moment.
You look displeased.
What's the matter?
The war in northwest
was originally a sure victory for me.
But the Crown Prince,
at this critical moment,
rushed to Tingxi City.
Just because you're facing
the Crown Prince,
you feel you have no chance of winning?
Changtai,
how long do we have to live in fear?
Can't you just let it go?
The other princes are Father's sons.
Some receive his favor,
some are groomed by him,
and one is his heir.
Why am I the only one
who is just a disposable pawn
in his chess game?
I want to make him regret
always looking down on me
and using me!
When my family was ruined
and I was left destitute,
you agreed to marry me
and treated me like a treasure.
Such kindness,
I will never forget until the day I die.
But your desire for power
has never ceased.
Before,
I was willing to take the blame for you,
hoping you would repent.
But in front of His Majesty,
you drank the so-called poisoned liquor,
playing the part of a devoted husband
to cover up your ambition.
Now you're even colluding
with foreign enemies to rebel.
Changtai,
it's not too late for us to stop now.
If we stop fighting for power,
wouldn't it be nice
to live a peaceful life?
But I can't accept that.
This is our only chance.
No matter what,
I have to take this gamble.
I understand.
I shouldn't have
expected anything from someone
who is driven mad by power.
Just be a good Princess Consort.
Geng Liangcheng has colluded
with the Le tribe army to mutiny
and attempt a rebellion.
The Duke of Wei and his son
are severely injured.
Especially the Duke of Wei,
who remains unconscious to this day.
Minister Tao,
where is the Crown Prince now?
The Crown Prince and Crown Princess
have arrived at Tingxi City.
Reporting to Your Majesty,
Prince Lie requests an audience.
Send him in.
Father, Changqing is handling
official business in Dianzhou.
Upon learning
of Geng Liangcheng's mutiny,
he sent a carrier pigeon asking me
to request an edict on his behalf.
He implores you to issue an order,
allowing him to dispatch
the troops stationed in Yaozhou
to support northwest
and quell the rebellion.
Your Majesty,
among the garrisons
in the nearby prefectures,
the one in Yaozhou is the most valiant
and battle-tested.
If they march through the mountain pass,
they can also arrive the fastest.
Granted.
Changying,
deliver my edict immediately.
Order him to do everything in his power
to protect the Crown Prince
and Crown Princess,
and ensure the safety
of the people in northwest.
I obey your command.
I'm truly tired.
Making the wrong choice
leads to a path of no return.
No!
I once promised you
that if there ever came a day
when I fell in love with you,
I would tell you immediately.
Xiao Huayong,
I love you.
♪I've hidden so many words♪
♪Too reluctant to tell you♪
♪So never uncover♪
♪The sand that slips away
with one grasp♪
♪The flower that withers
after one bloom♪
♪Silently buried deep inside my heart♪
♪Every answer I gave♪
♪Was both bittersweet and absurd♪
♪Hiding my tear-filled eyes
when I hurt you♪
♪How hard it truly was?♪
♪The wounds that healed
with just a little comfort♪
♪The lies made whole
with a single embrace♪
♪Pretending to be brave
as if I'd never been hurt♪
♪It's a shame I never could♪
♪Give you a moon in return♪
♪With the same open heart you loved me♪
♪I've crossed the wasteland of memories♪
♪Never knowing I was lost♪
♪Why don't you take me away?♪
♪Lead me out of this endless game
of hide-and-seek♪
♪You'll never♪
♪Know how much I long to, long to♪
(No animals were harmed
in the making of this film)